<preface id="strong-api-overview-strong">
 <title>API Overview</title>

 <para>Welcome to the Kubernetes API.  You can use the Kubernetes API to read
       and write Kubernetes resource objects via a Kubernetes API endpoint.</para>

 <sect1 id="resource-categories">
  <title>Resource Categories</title>

  <para>This is a high-level overview of the basic types of resources provided
        by the Kubernetes API and their primary functions.</para>
  <para><firstterm>Workloads</firstterm> are objects you use to manage and run
        your containers on the cluster.</para>
  <para><firstterm>Discovery &amp; LB</firstterm> resources are objects you use
        to "stitch" your workloads together into an externally accessible,
        load-balanced Service.</para>
  <para><firstterm>Config &amp; Storage</firstterm> resources are objects you
		use to inject initialization data into your applications, and to persist
		data that is external to your container.</para>
  <para><firstterm>Cluster</firstterm> resources objects define how the cluster
        itself is configured; these are typically used only by cluster operators.</para>
  <para><firstterm>Metadata</firstterm> resources are objects you use to
	    configure the behavior of other resources within the cluster, such as
	    <systemitem>HorizontalPodAutoscaler</systemitem> for scaling workloads.</para>
 </sect1>

 <sect1 id="resource-objects">
  <title>Resource Objects</title>

  <para>Resource objects typically have 3 components:</para>
  <variablelist>
   <varlistentry>
	<term>Resource ObjectMeta</term>
	<listitem><para>This is metadata about the resource, such as its name, type,
		api version, annotations, and labels.  This contains fields that maybe
		updated both by the end user and the system (e.g. annotations).</para>
	</listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   <varlistentry>
	<term>ResourceSpec</term>
	<listitem><para>This is defined by the user and describes the desired state
		of system.  Fill this in when creating or updating an object.</para>
	</listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   <varlistentry>
	<term>ResourceStatus</term>
	<listitem><para>This is filled in by the server and reports the current
		state of the system.  In most cases, users don't need to change this.</para>
	</listitem>
   </varlistentry>
  </variablelist>
 </sect1>

</preface>
